Nathaniel Afrifah-Adae

<u>nafrifahadae@gmail.com</u> | <u>www.linkedin.com/in/nathaniel-afrifah-adae/</u> <u>https://nathaniel-afrifah-adae.netlify.app/</u> | <u>www.github.com/nafrifahadae</u>

Professional Summary

Dedicated, detail-orientated problem solver with a firm foundation in engineering, branching into computer science and programming. Responsible team leader able to instil confidence in colleagues. Recently completed 12-week intensive bootcamp upskilling in software development, completing projects in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python and MySQL. Confident with database management and linking APIs to webpages. Committed to staying up to date with new frameworks and technologies within the industry. Ready to begin work with no notice period in a developer or engineer role, open to remote or hybrid working.

Key Skills

- Knowledge of network systems
- Critical thinking
- Teamwork
- Communicator
- Attention to detail
- Problem solving
- · Highly adaptable
- Time management
- Creative innovator

Technical Projects www.github.com/nafrifahadae

Personal portfolio displaying my projects and technical experiences using <u>React</u> and <u>Canva</u> to design it's layout

Weather-app web application using <u>JavaScript</u> and an <u>API</u> to provide accurate and quick responses, HTML and CSS used to style and design

Database storing previous Ballon D'or (footballer award) awards using <u>Python</u> and <u>MySQL</u> with CRUD abilities for user

Education

Level 3 Software Development, Just IT

Sep 2023 - Dec 2023

- Understood programming fundamentals and how to debug code
- Front end web development using HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript for responsive, enhanced user experience
- Improved user interface by integrating Python with MySQL, displaying backend knowledge with relational databases
- Currently working on Odin Project to enhance knowledge in Ruby on Rails, Node.js and the basics of Version Control e.g., Git/GitHub

Engineering + Applied Science, Aston University

Sep 2020 - Aug 2021

- Understood the basic principles of engineering and the power of teamwork
- Worked on group projects including building a wooden go-kart, taking into account force, stress, material properties and aerodynamics

GCSE & A-Level, Holy Family Catholic School

Sep 2012 - Aug 2020

- 10/10 A*-C GCSE inc. English Grade 8, Maths Grade 7 & Physics Grade A
- 3 A*-D A Level in Maths, Physics and Psychology

Experience

IT Technician, Ladbrokes Coral Group Ltd

May 2022 - June 2023

- Diagnosed and debugged network issues
- Worked with software tools like PowerBI to present and resolve data issues
- Serviced applications such as Omnia resulting in 43% faster runtime for clients
- Upheld overall maintenance of FOBT operating systems (gaming machines)

Part-time Concessions Waiter, Wembley Stadium

Feb 2018 - May 2022

- Calm and collected in high pressure environments inc. EURO 2020 FINAL and FA CUP FINAL 2018
- Providing high quality service whilst upkeeping employee relations
- Voted Top 2 restaurant by costumers for delivery and product knowledge

References available on request